Brown Family Papers, 1825-1912, 1965 (Bulk 1850-1894)
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- (Box-folder 1:38)
  - Three page printed leaflet titled "Pastoral Letter" and signed by S.R. Preston, January 1, 1881.
- (Box-folder 1:39)
  - Doctor's bill from H(arvey) & K(ent) Black to James C. Brown, 1882.
  - Bill for J.C. Brown from R.E. Hatcher totaling $39.56, September 14, 1882.
  - Letter to Jas C. Brown from Ch--- 40. But--- in Lynchburg, Virginia, June 12, 1882.
- (Box-folder 1:40)
  - Letter to Mrs. Ann E. Brown from her sister Mary concerning the "Baptist meeting" and who has been converted, January 25, 1883.
  - Printed "For Sale or Rent" sign for the land of James C. Brown, June 25, 1883.
  - Note from Waller R. --upls concerning the court suit of Bennet and Fagg, April 28, 1883.
  - County tax bill for John Brown totaling $53.39, October 23, 1883.
- (Box-folder 1:41)
  - Obituary of Mrs. Blanche Barnett (wife of N.D. Barnett), 1884.
  - Note concerning the suit between John Brown's Chancery and Howe and Robert Brown, June 19, 1884.
- (Box-folder 1:42)
  - Note from Re- Harris to James Brown asking him to pay $3.57 to D.H. Brown, June 5, 1885.
  - Obituary of Capt. Joseph H. Howe. He died on December 7, 1885.
  - Receipt from John Shee-an- to Jas Brown showing that Brown has paid his account in full, February 6, 1885.
  - Letter from "Lizzie" to "Aunt Annie" about Mr. ("Uncle") Giles Barnett's funeral, February 20, 1885.
- (Box-folder 1:43)
  - Note to J.C. Brown from Joseph M. Moore asking Brown to pay $1.00 to Mr Dowdy for carrying his mail for one year, 1886.
- (Box-folder 1:44)
  - List of work done on a graveyard from William Cromer. Not original list, 1887.
- (Box-folder 1:45)
  - Receipt from J.K. Montague stating that he received $26.35 from R.L. Brown in full account of J.C. Brown, March 13, 1888.
- (Box-folder 1:46)
  - Letter to Mrs. John Brown from Nannie Barnett in Bedford County, Virginia, May 15, 1889.
- (Box-folder 1:47)
  - County tax bill to Robt. L. Brown for property, income, etc. valued at $485.00, plus $2.00 capitation tax. The total tax was $9.29, 1891.
  - County tax bill to Mary E. Bell on 47 acres land, valued at $1430.00. The total tax was $19.74, 1891.
- (Box-folder 1:48)
  - County tax bill to James C. Brown for capitation tax of $1 and county levy of $.50 totaling $1.50, 1892.
- (Box-folder 1:49)
  - Doctor bill from Dr. W.F. Henderdon to James C. Brown, January 12, 1893.
  - Obituary of Mrs. Martha Alexander Bell. She died on December 30 1893, in Lexington, West Virginia, 1893.
- (Box-folder 1:50)
  - Funeral notice of Mary Hite who died on July 15, 1894.
- (Box-folder 1:51)
  - County tax bill to Jas. C. Brown totaling $1.50 (2 copies), 1899.
- (Box-folder 1:52)
  - Note from Hall & Woods Attorneys at Law stating that the fee for drawing release deed from H.T. Hall to H.M. Johnston is $5.00, 1912.
- (Box-folder 1:53)
  - "The Browns of Roanoke Valley," a story and history of the Brown family written by Frances Parker Brown, December 1965.
- (Box-folder 1:54)
  - Poems written for Miss Ann E. Barnett, author unknown.
  - Letter, author and receiver unknown.
  - Unfinished letter to Dr. Black, author unknown.
  - Price list from Valley Mills Foundry in Middle River, Augusta Co., Virginia.
  - Letter from D.H. Hoge to James Brown insisting on being paid.
  - Torn general merchandise bill of James Brown in account with -- Obernhain.
  - Photocopy of a general merchandise bill for John Brown from A.W. Luster.
  - One page of a letter from Pickett explaining that he is working on the railroad.
  - Three envelopes, two are addressed to Miss Annie Barnett and the other one addressed to D. Cephallus Black.
  - Pressed and dried flowers and leaves.
  - Letter to "Aunt" (Mrs.John Brown?) from Cynthia.
  - Announcement that "The People's Book" will be published as soon as enough people subscribe.
  - Envelope addressed to Alexandria, Virginia, to Robert Bell.
  - A flowery thought signed by Miss Fannie C. Thomas.
  - A flowery thought, author unknown.
  - Bill of lumber and carpentry for granary.
  - Letter from Fanny McBullock, teacher,to James Brown concerning a job offer from Giles Thomas.
  - Letter form Maggie to Miss Ann.
  - Note from A.J. Ellen to Mr. J. Brown telling him to let George have $2.50 on his account.
  - Letter from Martha to Annie.
  - Letter to Annie Barnett from Annie concerning the death of a child (Pet).
  - List of political candidates.
  - Letter from Annie to her sister.
  - Letter from Wm. B. Morton to Mr. Brown concerning land that Brown wants to buy in Botetourt.
  - Letter from Ella to Aunt Annie.
  - Two envelopes addressed to James Brown.
  - Invitation for dinner from Lizzie A. Langhorne to Miss Ann.
  - Handwritten love poem, author unknown
  - Letter from Annie Barnett to her dear sister.
  - Letter from Ell to Ann Thomas concerning molasses cakes.
  - Letter from Ann E.B. consoling her cousin in time of death.
  - Bill from J.C. Brown to J.T. miller concerning clerk's and attorney's fees.
  - Note from W.H. ------- to H.S. Hill explaining that he cleaned the wheat very well and made it into flour.
  - Short note from W.S. to Miss Ann thanking her for a nice bouquet.
  - Envelope addressed to Miss Annie Barnett.
  - Note to James Brown from J.H. Hemming, bootmaker.
  - Short note stating, "Capt Kent will be pleased to see you at Edgehill on Tuesday evening August 22 at 8 o'clock."
  - Envelope addressed to James Barnett & family, Shawsville.
  - Note to James Brown explaining that he owes $200.00, author unknown.
  - Letter to Miss Annie Barnett, author unknown, envelope enclosed.
- (Box-folder 1:55)
  - Newspaper clippings of John C. Brown's obituary and death.
  - Newspaper clipping of Dr. Kent Black's obituary.
  - Newspaper clipping of John Barnett's obituary.
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings that have been torn.
  - Small fold up catalog for the "New Remington Sewing Machine."
- (Box-folder 1:56)
  - "Inventory of papers found in old trunk in attic of James Brown's Farmhouse" referring to paper listed here.
- (Box-folder 1:57)
  - The Brown Home (genealogy and history of Brown home on the North Fork of the Roanoke River in Montgomery County, Virginia).